rebeccaelizabethtay.com

rebeccatay92@gmail.com

Rebecca E. Tay

I'm a full stack developer with experience in React, Redux, GraphQL and Postgres. I like building things knowing that I am able to change the lives of others through my code. I believe in approaching my journey as a developer with the growth mindset; to stretch my limits and grow day by day.

Experience

Co-founder, Full Stack Developer. Domato Devs Pte Ltd | Sep 2017 - Jul 2018

- Worked on developing a prototype for an itinerary planning web application. (See projects)
- Worked on React frontend with Redux for state management. Converted wireframes into React components and implemented desired user flows.
- Integrated mapping, location search and geocoding APIs into user interface for visualization of day by day plans.
- Implemented user authentication and authorization using OAuth and dynamic routing. Experimented with user uploads of media content via Google Cloud Storage.
- Set up GraphQL-Express-Postgres backend for flexible querying of the database, using custom GraphQL types and type resolution to output the structure frontend needed.
- Refactored GraphQL resolvers from promises to async/await, resulting in up to 30% less lines and improved code readability.

Education Officer, National Institute of Education | Aug 2015 - Nov 2016

• Underwent training for the Postgraduate Diploma in Education for Biology and Math.

Education

General Assembly, Web Development Immersive | Jun 2017 - Sep 2017

 Studied in an intensive 12 week bootcamp encompassing fundamentals and popular frameworks. Gained exposure to React, Postgres, MongoDB, Express, Ruby on Rails

FreeCodeCamp | Apr 2017 - Jun 2017

Taught myself Javascript from the front-end curriculum, to prepare myself for bootcamp.

NUS, BSc. Life Sciences | Aug 2011 - Jun 2015

 Specialized in environmental biology. Worked with R and ArcGIS to produce geospatial predictive model of cropland expansion in Myanmar.

Projects

Marco https://domatodevs.herokuapp.com/

An itinerary planning and travel content site. Users are able to plan itineraries easily and view information about trips others are taking. Users are able to use the map to view day by day plans, search for and add locations easily. Users are also able to save locations visited by others into their bucket list, which can then be added in their itinerary. A dashboard is available to access itineraries and created content.

React | Redux | Apollo | GraphQL | Express | Postgres | OAuth | Mapping API

KryptoKnight https://kryptoknight.herokuapp.com/

Cryptocurrency education tool providing budding investors with technical analysis and a simulated brokerage.

JQuery | Ruby on Rails | Postgres

Magic Mango https://magicmango.herokuapp.com/

DOTA2 strategy site. Create, save and view item builds for different play styles.

JQuery | Express | MongoDB

Build-A-Burger https://rebeccatay92.github.io/project-1/

My very first project in bootcamp. Build-A-Burger is a vanilla JS game where the player click ingredients in the right order and fulfil tickets within the time given.

HTML | CSS | Javascript

Skills

Frontend: React, Redux

Backend: Node, Express, Apollo-GraphQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Others: Git, Google Maps, Mapbox, OAuth2.0, Google Cloud Storage

General: HTML, CSS, Javascript